# **NEIL CASAANDRA**

A QA Engineer with more than 9 years of experience in ensuring the quality and reliability of software products and services. I have expertise in test planning, manual testing, automated testing, API testing, and database testing and others. Currently pursuing Master Degree in IT - Data Analytics, to boarden my horizon in the industry.

#### **Contacts**

**\** 0466534573

neilsudharmono@gmail.com

Newcastle, NSW

in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/neil-casaandra-b72308a7/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/neil-casaandra-b72308a7/</a>

#### Certifications

ISTQB Foundation Level ISTQB Performance Tester

**IELTS** 7.5 **PTE** 77

#### Skills

Test Planning, Execution, and Report

Test Case / Scenarios management (Testrail, XRAY,

Spreadsheet)

**Manual & Exploratory Testing** 

API Testing (Postman, Swagger)

CMS Testing (Kentico, Optimizely, Kontent, Sitecore, Umbraco)

Automated Testing (Cypress)
Load Testing (JMeter, K6, Flood)

Compatibility Testing (Browserstack, DevTools, Actual Devices)

Database Testing (SQL, MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL)

**Accessibility testing** (Wave, Lighthouse, Chrome DevTools)

Agile Team Management (JIRA, Confluence, Tempo, etc.)

Basic Programming (Java, Javascript, Python)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Sudo Roux, Sydney

Jan 2023 - Present

# Senior QA Engineer - Remote Full Time to Freelance

- · Create QA standards within the company,
- Test plans creation, developing scenarios, conducting manual, exploratory and CMS testing,
- · Ensuring the products' compatibility,
- Documenting Test Report, Release Note, and as-built details for each project.
- Load testing

Notable Projects: Sydney Royal Easter Show, Royal Agriculture Society of NSW, Sydney Showground College of Law, Mother Hubbard Ime

Xendit, Singapore Nov 2022 - Jan 2023

 Product testing, conducted Test planning, test scenario development, using Cypress.io and Codecept.js for automated testing, manual testing, API testing with Postman, and checking databases with Postgresql, help in interviewing junior QA before they join the team.

Brankas, Singapore April 2022 - Nov 2022

### Senior QA Engineer - Remote Full Time

 Product Testing, conducted test planning, scenario development, reporting, utilizing Cypress.io for automated testing, manual testing, API testing with Postman, and database checking with Postgresql for Fintech product, mentor junior QA team members and train them to meet company

Luminary, Melbourne Oct 2019 - April 2022

# QA Analyst - Remote Full Time

- I've worked across diverse industries including Super, Charity, Electrical, and E-commerce for Australian companies,
- Conducted test planning, scenario development, reporting, manual testing, automated testing with Cypress.io, API testing using Postman, and performance testing with tools like K6 and Flood.io.
- CMS testing on platforms such as Kentico Xperience, Umbraco, Sitecore, Kontent, and Optimizely,
- Conducted accessibility testing using WAVE, Compatibility testing via Browserstack
- Client walkthroughs and mentoring junior QA team members.

**Notable Projects**: Clipspec by Clipsal, Fred Hollows, Cancer Council, EISS Super, LUCRF Super, Healthy Life & Pet Culture by Woolworths

The Development Studio, Bali April 2019 - Oct 2019

### Test Analyst - Full Time

 Did Test planning, scenario development, and reporting for e-learning web application products, manual and automated testing using Cypress.io for automated testing and Postman for API testing. I used Testrail, Confluence, and JIRA for testing management, performance testing using JMeter

Notable Projects: E2Language and E2School

DGIT, Melbourne Nov 2017 - Mar 2019

### Quality Analyst - Full Time

- Collaborating with a distributed team across New Zealand, Australia, South Africa, and the UAE for implementation of Telflow product.
- Conducted test planning, scenario creation, and reporting utilizing Testrail
  and JIRA. My proficiency extends to automated testing using Selenium with
  Cucumber, API testing with SoapUI, and performance testing employing
  JMeter and Grafana.
- Database testing, specifically with MongoDB. Implementing continuous integration with DevOps, particularly leveraging Jenkins, I contribute to seamless testing of Elastic Search.

OCBC NISP Bank, Bandung July 2014 - Oct 2017

### Quality Analyst - Full Time

- Responsible for manual testing on desktop, web application and AS400 systems for banking with, test planning, test scenario development beforehand. In addition, i also debugged issue with Visual Studio and SQL Profiler, as well as database testing with SQL Server.
- Moreover, i led manual deployment in UAT and production environments, I
  ensure seamless transitions. As a source code gatekeeper using Visual
  Sourcesafe, my expertise contributes to robust core bank testing,
  particularly with AS400 systems.

### **EDUCATION**

King's Own Institute 2023 - present

### Master of Information Technology - Data Analytics

Newcastle, NSW, Australia

Maranatha Christian University 2010 - 2014

### **Bachelor of Information Technology**

Bandung, Indonesia - GPA 3.56 / 4.00

### REFERENCES

Luminary

Matthew Stobo, QA Manager and Senior Front End Developer

mjstobo@gmail.com 0403275041

Sudo Roux

Dillon Hicks, CEO

<u>dillon.hicks@sudoroux.com.au</u> 1300753499